Guide to the John Browne, Commonplace Book
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
[Papers: collection of documents from his papers relating to the Popish Plot]
1678-1679
OSBORN FB153
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.02
(1 volume)
Collection of seven manuscripts, in multiple hands, concerning the Popish Plot, primarily of testimonies and accusations. The collection contains a letter by an unnamed woman to Coventry promising to deliver to him the names of many priests and Jesuits for a promised reward, as well as Coventry's reply assuring her she will be paid. Other items include a report on the death of Sir Edmund Berry Godfrey; King Charles II's speech to the House of Lords in 1678; a signed statement by Sir John Werden, declaring that he had been sent by the Duke of York to Titus Oates to confirm that Oates had spoken with Sir Thomas Williams; and a signed statement by Roger Hyett declaring that John Birch had accused the Queen and the Duke of York of being Papists.
Coventry, Henry, 1619-1686
Immediate Source of Acquisition
For provenance information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The following finding aid is a complete inventory of the contents of Osborn fb155. This list was reformatted from previously existing cataloging.
Legal documents; Popish Plot, 1678; Women authors; Great Britain -- Politics and government -- 1660-1688; Great Britain -- Religious life and customs -- 17th century; Catherine, of Braganza, Queen, consort of Charles II, King of England, 1638-1705; Charles, King of England, II, 1630-1685; James, King of England, II, 1633-1701; Birch, John, 1615-1691; Coventry, Henry, 1619-1686; Godfrey, Edmund Berry, Sir, 1621-1678; Godfrey, Edmund Berry, Sir, 1621-1678 -- Assassination; Oates, Titus, 1649-1705; Werden, John, Sir, 1640-1716; Great Britain. Parliament. House of Lords; Catholic Church -- Protestant authors -- Controversial literature
- Osborn fb153
  - COVENTRY, SIR HENRY (1619-86)
    - Letter (draft) to unnamed recipient., 1678 Dec 19 (Box 1)
      Scope and Contents
      n.p.
      1 p.; 24 x 19 cm.
      Response to an enclosed letter from
      a woman in Paris offering to reveal
      Papists, and promising payment.
  - [REPORT]
    - Concerning the death of Sir Edmund Berry Godfrey (1621-78).], 1678 Oct 20 (Box 1)
      3 p.; 22 x 18 cm.
      Anonymous Manuscript.
  - HYETT, ROGER
    - Document, signed, 1679 May 10 (Box 1)
      Norton Canon.
      1 p.; 31 x 20 cm.
      States that John Birch (1616-91) had
      accused the Queen and Duke of York
      of being Papists.
      Catherine of Braganza, Queen consort
      of Charles II, 1638-1705; James II,
      King of Great Britain, 1633-1701.
  - CHARLES II, KING OF GREAT BRITAIN (1630-85)
    - [Speech to the House of Lords, 9 Nov 1678.], n.d. (Box 1)
      1 p.; 25 x 19 cm.
      Contemporary MS copy. Also includes
      part of a reply by the Lord
      Chancellor, Sir John Duncombe.
  - WERDEN, SIR JOHN, BART., 1640-1716
    - Document, signed, 1679 Sep 24 (Box 1)
      Whitehall.
      1 p.; 30 x 19 cm.
      States that he had been sent that
      day by the Duke of York to Titus
      Oates (1648-1705), who claimed to
      have had a discussion with Sir
      Thomas Williams.